Guide to the James Rockwell Sheffield Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Wadsworth, James Wolcott, Jr. 1918 Oct 29 1921 Jan 8; Apr 22; Mar 9; May 12; Jul 13 1922 Apr 1; Jul 18; Nov 10 1923 May 1; Jul 21; Sep 19
Welling, Richard W. G. 1903 Oct 9; Nov 4
Whitehouse, Sheldon 1929 Nov 8
Wickersham, George Woodward 1909 Dec 21 1911 May 22 1928 Mar 19 1934 Aug 13
Williams, William 1928 Dec 4, 6
Young, Owen D. 1934 Aug 13
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in three series: I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1768-1969. II. SCRAPBOOKS, 1893-1940. III. PERSONAL PAPERS, 1868-1938.
Civil service reform; Law; Latin America; Mexico -- Foreign relations -- United States; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Saybrook (Conn.); United States -- Foreign relations -- Mexico; United States -- Foreign relations -- Venezuela; United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1933; Venezuela -- Foreign relations -- United States; Memoirs; Photoprints; Scrapbooks; Diplomats; Lawyers; Politicians; Allison, William B. (William Boyd), 1829-1908; Anderson, Chandler P. (Chandler Parsons), 1866-1936; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Hotchkiss, Frederick William, 1762-1844; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948; Jennings, Oliver Gould, 1865-1936; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937; Lane, Arthur Bliss, 1894-1956; Morrow, Dwight W. (Dwight Whitney), 1873-1931; Olds, Robert Edwin, 1875-1932; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Schoenfeld, Hans Frederick Arthur, 1889-1952; Sheffield, James R. (James Rockwell), 1864-1938; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1877-1952; Weddell, Alexander Wilbourne, 1876-1948; White, Edward Douglass, 1845-1921; New York (N.Y.). Board of Fire Commissioners; National Republican Club, Inc; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Correspondence, 1768-1969; Series I; 4.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in four sections: General, Letterpress copybooks, Family, and Miscellanea.
  General and Letterpress copybooks files are arranged in chronological order. Family and Miscellanea are arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual.
  - General
    - 1878 - 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
    - 1897 - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 11-20)
    - 1902 - 1909 (Box 3, Folder 21-30)
    - 1910 - 1920 (Box 4, Folder 31-42)
    - 1921 - 1927 May (Box 5, Folder 43-53)
    - 1927 June - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 54-62)
    - 1932 - 1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 63-72)
  - Letterpress copybooks
    - 1914 April-1916 January (Box 8, Folder 73-75)
    - 1916 January - 1922 July (Box 9, Folder 76-79)
  - Family
    - Hotchkiss, Frederick William, 1788-1840 (Box 10, Folder 80-81)
    - Hotchkiss, Susan J., 1811-1849 (Box 10, Folder 82-83)
    - Sheffield, Amelia Hart, 1798-1842 (Box 10, Folder 84-85)
    - Sheffield, Amelia Hotchkiss, 1838-1879 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Sheffield, Amos, 1824-1845 (Box 10, Folder 87-88)
    - Sheffield, Edith, 1909-1938 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Sheffield, Frederick, 1909-1969 (Box 10, Folder 90-91)
    - Sheffield, Frederick William, 1840-1868 (Box 10, Folder 92-93)
    - Sheffield, Henry H., 1871-1877 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - Sheffield, Sarah Kellogg, 1871-1898 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Tod, Sarah Keys, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Others, 1873-1893 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Others, 1894-1934 (Box 11, Folder 98-99)
  - Miscellanea
    - First Church of Saybrook: notes, 1768-1896, undated (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Rev. Hotchkiss, Frederick: notes, 1810-1817 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Sheffield family, financial records, 1792-1824 (Box 11, Folder 102)
- Scrapbooks, 1893-1940; Series II; 4 linear feet (8 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: General and Photographs. Each section is arranged in chronological order.
  - General
    - 1893 October - 1895 May (Box 12, Folder 103-104)
    - 1895 June - 1897 September (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - 1897-1900 (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - 1901-1909 (Box 14, Folder 107-108)
    - 1910-1923 (Box 15, Folder 109-110)
    - 1924 August - 1925 June (Box 16, Folder 111)
    - 1925 May - 1926 March (Box 16, Folder 112)
    - 1926 May - 1928 February (Box 17, Folder 113-114)
    - 1927 May - 1935 (Box 18, Folder 115)
    - 1928 - 1938 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Photographs
    - 1926 - 1940 (Box 19, Folder 117)
- Personal Papers, 1868-1938; Series III; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by record type.
  - Autobiography, undated (Box 20, Folder 118)
  - Certificates and awards, 1893-1938 (Box 20, Folder 119-120)
  - Speeches
    - Vols. 1-3, 1890-1935 (Box 20, Folder 121-124)
    - Vols. 4; 6-8, 1890-1935 (Box 21, Folder 125-128)
    - Printed, 1897-1933 (Box 21, Folder 129-130)
  - Topical files
    - Campaign of 1893 (Box 21, Folder 131)
    - New York politics, 1893-1916 (Box 22, Folder 132)
    - Presentation of statue of Henry Clay to Venezuela by the U.S., 1930 December (Box 22, Folder 133)
  - Writings, 1893-1935, undated (Box 22, Folder 134-136)
  - Miscellaneous, 1868-1938 (Box 22, Folder 137)
  - George Washington's speech declining a reelection to the Office of President, 1796, printed by Hudson and Goodwin, Hartford (Box 23)
    General note
    See: CF56
- Additional Material, Accession 2003-M-006
  - Bound volume containing signatures of members of the Committee on the Sheffield Portrait and staff members of the American Embassy in Mexico, presented to James Sheffield at the time of his retirement as ambassador to Mexico, 1926 (Box 1)